Eduardo Luiz da Silveira

Software Engineer

Rua Almirante Barroso 3121, Ap 41, Toledo PR - Brazil +55 (45) 99146-4369 | eduardoluizsilveira@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elsilveira/ https://elsilveira.github.io/eduardosilveira/

I am a full-stack developer with expertise in Javascript and Typescript. I navigate easily between frameworks, including Angular and React.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Core Skills

- HTML, HTML5
- Javascript, Typescript
- CSS, SCSS
- Angular
- AngularJS

Secondary Skills

- C#, .NET
- Dart, Flutter, Angulardart
- React, Vue, Ionic
- SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Fullstack Engineer

Group BMW (Zallpy) | REMOTE | Jun 2023 - Present

- Angular and C# Developer
- Developing a financial platform for BMW USA, CANADA and MEXICO
- Software to generate and manage deals.
- The role includes a lot of engineering work, analysis and automated tests.
- By clearing and refactoring the deals flow, I've achieved stability and significantly reduced the delay and errors on managing deals.

Senior Fullstack Developer

Vengreso, Walnut Creek(CA) | REMOTE | Aug 2023 - Present

- Angular 16 and React Browser Extension developer.
- Working on DOM manipulation from a browser extension, communication with Al.
- Working on a dashboard for efficient management of shortcuts, data, and plans.
- Engaged in strategic planning within a fast-paced startup environment.
- Initiatives to enhance team processes, optimize Git usage, and ensure stable project versions.

Senior Frontend Software Engineer

Layer, Dublin(IE) | REMOTE | Dec 2020 - Aug 2023

- Angular Dart, Angular 16 and Flutter Developer
- Working with different banks around the world to implement their web banking solution.
- Working in foreign team of at least 4 different countries.
- The role includes a lot of engineering work, focused on performance and reusability.
- Developing a brand-new bank as a service platform on angular 16.
- Development of a web SDK and related component library in angular 16 to be distributed as part of the banking platform.

• Senior Web Engineer

TRIO, Boston(MA) | REMOTE | Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

- Ionic and Angular Developer
- Working on a social learning platform to create a web curriculum and learning platform.
- Working closely to design to improve user experience and reusability.
- Developed a brand-new learning platform on angular 14, with streaming, games and interactive videos.

System Developer

EASYCOMTEC, Miami(FL) | REMOTE | Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

- Ionic, Angular and C# Developer
- Developed two mobile apps, KickOne Social Media and Car Washx

System Developer

DATACOPER, Cascavel (BR) | LOCAL | Mar 2016 - Jan 2017

- C#, .Net Forms, Xamarin, Android and Windows Phone Developer
- Worked in the CRM team and was responsible for the Android App, Windows App, iOS App, and Web App (Web Forms)

System Developer

INSIDE SISTEMAS, Toledo (BR) | LOCAL | Dec 2012 - Jan 2015

- Adobe Flex and C# Developer
- Played a significant role in translating a Visual Basic software into an cloud with Flex

EDUCATION

System Analyst and Development
Universidade Paranaense (UNIPAR) | January 2011 - July 2015

Idiomas

Portuguese	English
Native	C1